

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Current Designation: System Engineer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

Current Company: Wipro Limited Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Mumbai Highest Degree: BA [History]

Pref. Location: Mumbai, Singapore, Dubai

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance Role: System Admin

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services
Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: System Engineer, System Admin, Desktop Support, Network Support, Installation, Network Security, Technical Support, System Administration, IT Infrastructure Management, Troubleshooting, Problem Management, IT Helpdesk

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Work Authorization

Management,Incident Management,DNS Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 25-Aug-20 Last Modified: 25-Aug-20

Summary

Jump to Section

Learning is a curve that never ends, and I believe that thirst when combined with sheer hard work and determination can bring success to one's life which I feel I am an example and proud of it. I have joined in the role of a Systems Engineer Trainee in December 2015 and progressed to Systems Engineer; Senior systems Engineer with my current role as Engineering Analyst. I have been associated with different companies for the past 3 years, 10 months and working with multiple clients has given me better understanding of any Manufacturing or services-based industries.

believe in securing a responsible career opportunity to fully utilize my skills and training, while making a significant contribution to success of the organization I work for while gaining knowledge in newer things and expanding my horizons.

Work Experience

Wipro Limited as System Engineer Sep 2019 to Till Date

1|Page

Vara United & Wipro Limited- Working for Client ICICI Bank

Tenure of services: 10th Sept ?19 to Present

Responsibilities

Ensure standardization, compliance and enforcement of user access policies and daily operating procedures Troubleshooting issue related to mail flow, mail restrictions and email related issue via exchange server Working with the automation team to get the things automated for reducing human efforts.

Regularly housekeeping of AD Domains

Preparing AD Audit data and maintain the list of MP Users

Looking after the escalations from senior users and on priority requests until the closure

Performing No login activity to get the report of non-active users for all location

Responsible for mailbox creation and setting up email account for new joinee

Monitoring and scheduling of batch file jobs.

Preparation of daily server checklist & team activity reports

Working on Ms Exchange and troubleshooting issue related to the same.

Management of User account- Creation , deletion, modification and Disable

Handling request for generic id creation and DL Creation and responsible for applying the restriction on the sameAnalyzing and troubleshooting basic issue of PC.

Working with different team on different project and looking after their requirements as a part of operations.

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Union Bank Of Switzerland as IT Analyst

Feb 2018 to Sep 2019

Successfully lead & executed project in Singapore for Expert Layer Support. Achieved milestones by training the team & implementing the process from scratch in India.

Installation of OS and recovering the system remotely as per request on security team.

Providing user remote support for L1 and L2 service as per request and troubleshooting for issue related to desktop & laptops

To provide support and coordinate with clients during PM (preventive maintenance) activity.

Maintaining Incident management, Problem management, Change management, trackers.

Coordinating with concerned teams to resolve issues regarding network, server etc.

Working with the problem management team & helping team by creating awareness and performing the steps required to resolve the issue as per the guidelines of Microsoft

Provide L1 & L2 troubleshooting for issue related to VDI & DTP machines Troubleshooting issues related to local as well as roaming profiles for global users.

Handling issues related to sync centre and C drive full issues in VDI environment

Troubleshooting issues related to Market Data Products.

Troubleshooting issues related to Moonshot- A3 dedicated VDI

Part of mission control team by being an active member in troubleshooting all outage taking place within the organization environment

Responsible for Internal co-ordination with all departments for technical issues

Troubleshooting issues related to Windows Updates & Software Failures in VDI Infrastructure

Quota Management for Share drive

Applying Gsnow Helsinki ticketing tool during projects

Compiling & presenting information upon resolving project related issue.

Handling Frequent account lockout issue via Dell Change Auditor (Active directory Tool)

Troubleshooting issues related to Group share drive on users system and handling access related issue in Active

Using Netmon and Procmon tools to capture the logs for frequent issue

Troubleshooting Outlook, Internet, Softwares and antivirus issue

Analyzing and troubleshooting basic issue of PC.

Wipro InfoTech as Windows System Engineer

Dec 2015 to Sep 2019

InfoTech - On 3rd Party Payroll of Embee Software Pvt Ltd and ThinkApps Solutions Pvt Ltd at client site Colgate Global **Business Services**

of service: 16th Nov 2015 to 10th Feb'2018 Responsibilities:

Managing & handling team for end user support & Global Support

Manage & maintain IT Systems along with Vendors Management.

Maintaining an Optimizing Software & Hardware Inventory.

Coordinating & supporting Internal departments with technical support

Responsible for weekly checkup of Microsoft Server Patch & Access Management

Monitoring & managing server backup & restorations

Troubleshooting of basic network issues, VPN, SCCM, Bit Lockers, Windows Update and windows profile related problems.

Provide support to mail clients (Google, Lotus Notes)

Involved in DR planning & server restart activities

RSA Administration- assigning token to the end users as per requirements and trouble shooting of issues related to RSA

Complaint management and providing best of customer services to internal / external customers

Active Directory House Keeping.

Share Drive quota management for end users via file server

Provide share drive access via active directory to end user

Providing Cross Domain access to end user via Active Directory

Deletion of Unwanted shared drive via active directory by seeking the proper approval from management

Performing weekly checkup of IT Equipment's and logging calls with vendor in case of hardware issue.

^ Back to Ton

Education

UG: B.A (History) from Mumbai University in 2015

PG: BA (History) from Mumbai University in 2015

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Global Networking & Infrastructure Managemen

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Microsoft Office	
MCSA	
MCSE	
AZURE	

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				

Hindi	
Marathi	

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Countries: Australia, Switzerland, Singapore Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.